<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cycling | Bird Stream]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.adambird.com/blog/categories/cycling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.adambird.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-17T22:36:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.adambird.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hautacam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambird.com/hautacam"/>
    <updated>2013-08-18T21:19:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambird.com/hautacam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is a strong correlation between having Hautacam on your TdF palmares and performance enhancement through drugs. I took the opposite approach and rode it with a mild hangover.</p>

<iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/75540184/embed/58d175651805aebc2049b2bacecac14f3c4ac4d6'></iframe>


<p>I got chatting to a local cyclist at one of the campsite dinners who told me how beautiful this climb was. Also, the start of the climb was only about 8km from where we are staying so I couldn't not do.</p>

<p>However, it turned out to be lot harder than I was anticipating.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The pattern of this climb is one of reported average gradients bearing little correlation to the actual gradients you experience.</p>

<p>A reported 8% km section is inevitably several flatter sections followed by ramps of more than 10%. For some reason I thought this climb got easier about halfway up but saw no evidence until in the final 2km. I was out of my saddle for more on this climb than any of the others I'd done in the Pyrenees over the last week.</p>

<p>The lower slopes are tree-lined and in morning shade that makes the torture slightly more bearable.</p>

<p>Around about 6km from the end the good stuff really starts to happen. Amazing views across the valleys that meet at Argeles-Gazost.</p>

<p>Across the Val d'Azun with the Soulor and Aubisque Cols at it's head and the Pic des Tourettes, whose name entertained the schoolboy in me, towering over. And up towards Cauterets with Vignemale, the tallest mountain in the French Pyrenees. The ascent up to Hautacam being on the western side, these were all bathed in morning sun.</p>

<p>After a punishing 2km from around 5km to go things started to get easier and it's possible to take in the view now the trees no longer line the road. I had the usual Pyrenean livestock to negotiate and the last km was an easy run round to the TdF finish.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/adambird/9539109144/" title="Hautacam finish by adamebird, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5485/9539109144_f49f3523c0.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Hautacam finish"></a></p>

<p>What I then discovered, after taking the obligatory photo opp, was that there was still another 1.2km to go up to the top of Col de Tramessel. There you'll find a refuge and the start of several Nordic ski routes and views over the other side of the Hautacam massif.</p>

<p>The descent was, again, brilliant. Lot's more of accelerating out hairpins in the big ring and really feeling like you're living the dream. I've come to the conclusion that the real danger on Pyrenean descents is hitting some fresh livestock poo. Terrifying when you come hurtling round a bend and find shiny brown splodges across the road.</p>

<p>One more cycling day to go. I think I'm going to try something a little off the beaten track for my last excursion.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/adambird/9539122244/" title="The finishing markings from the 2008 finish by adamebird, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7341/9539122244_dc684f9e32.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="The finishing markings from the 2008 finish"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Col du Tourmalet]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambird.com/col-du-tourmalet"/>
    <updated>2013-08-15T18:25:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambird.com/col-du-tourmalet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was Jérémy Roy</p>

<iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/74848523/embed/79861b92c9d6541ca3dcc1db7597fbd8a0947e75'></iframe>


<p>The plan today was to take in both ascents of the Col du Tormalet. We're staying close (20km) to the start of the west ascent so and out, up and over, and back seemed like a 'sensible' plan.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The one challenge was the road closures due to the flood damage experienced earlier in the season between Barèges and Luz-Saint-Sauveur, the first section of the climb. The roads were closed from 08:00 to 12:00 and 13:30 to 17:30. So in order to make sure I was passed the roadworks before they closed I had to leave at 05:45 so I could descend back home during the lunchtime period.</p>

<p>This wasn't so bad as it meant, after a ride to Luz in the dark, I had the climb to myself. It seemed no one else was fool as me. The climb starts pretty much straight out of Luz with 7-9% sections all the way up to Barèges. It was on this section that I discover the devastation the Le Bastan river had wraught. Fast melting, unusually high snow fall had ripped mercilessly through the valley tearing homes and roads apart.</p>

<p>As you go past 10km to go the road flattens to 5% which seems blessed relief at the time. As you round the bend at the end of the first flatter section you get a glimpse of your destination. The notch in the ridge ahead of you is the chairlift a few hundred metres south of the road pass itself.</p>

<p>After an easy section through the ski station at Super-Barèges things start to ramp up again and you can't help feeling this is where it all starts to kick off when the Col is the destination for a summit finish. It's at this point that the road painting starts to appear. Including a timely reminder that 'pain is weakness leaving the body'.</p>

<object width="400" height="300"> <param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&lang=en-us&page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fadambird%2Fsets%2F72157635086805664%2Fshow%2F&page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fadambird%2Fsets%2F72157635086805664%2F&set_id=72157635086805664&jump_to="></param> <param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=124984"></param> <param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=124984" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&lang=en-us&page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fadambird%2Fsets%2F72157635086805664%2Fshow%2F&page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fadambird%2Fsets%2F72157635086805664%2F&set_id=72157635086805664&jump_to=" width="400" height="300"></embed></object>


<p>More curious comes at around 5km to go when there is a Dutch section with names of national riders followed by what appears to be 500m of 1-3m long sperm. If I hadn't been cycling I would have taken a photo so you'll just have to believe me. Would love to know what it's about.</p>

<p>Just at the end of the sperm, if you look up to your left you can see the observatory balanced precariously on the top of the Pic du Midi. Completely oblivious to your plight as all it's attention is focused on the heavens.</p>

<p>2km is when it gets really serious. There's a flat'ish section until a righthand hairpin at which point it's a push skyward to the summit. Time to get into that pain cave and feel right at home as there is no respite now until the top. When you round the final lefthand hairpin under the chairlift any thoughts of an elegant, seated approach evaporate as the gradient, coupled with it's position on the climb, require every muscle you can muster to overcome it.</p>

<p>I was alone on the Col at 08:30 when I arrived so a quick snap and straight down the other side to the ski resort at La Mongie, 4km below the Col, for what I hoped would be breakfast. Unfortunately all I could find open was a bar that was just serving coffee. A couple of short ones and I was off down what felt like would be the best descent of the day.</p>

<p>The 8km from La Mongie consisted of long straights and open corners that you could see through. I'm no dare-devil descender so didn't push it, especially with some new wheels that I haven't got used to yet, but I felt confident and enjoyed every minute of it. Maybe partly down to a masochistic pleasure taken in knowing I'd be coming back up shortly.</p>

<p>I stopped at Sainte-Marie de Campan, the start of the east ascent, turned straight around and started the ascent up. The first part is very easy, 3-4% easy, and at this point I was feeling pretty pleased with myself. One ascent done and feeling strong for the next one. Two things put pay to that confidence.</p>

<p>Firstly the sun. Although it was only around 10:00 this side of the valley was bathed in strong sunshine. The first climb had been in glorious, early morning shade. I'd taken great pleasure in watching as the sun first picked out the peaks on the opposite side of the valley and slowly crept down, illuminating them with a warm glow. This side was just unrelentingly hot. I remembered far more trees on the descent, though in reality the open sections just went past more quickly when I was hurtling down.</p>

<p>Secondly the climbing was quite different. This is purported to be the easier side but I found it a relentless 8-10% slog. Those long straights with open corners were reminiscent of the climb up Ventoux from Bedoin where there is no respite whatsoever for miles. I accept that I wasn't necessarily approaching the climb with fresh legs but any dreams I had of arriving fresh at the top quickly disappeared.</p>

<p>As I approached La Mongie again I formed a loose agreement with a more senior French rider, sporting a local club's jersey, a substantial grey mustache and astride a beautiful steel Colnago of some reasonable vintage. We worked together through and out of the inelegant architecture of the ski-station. It felt quite surreal with tourists arriving and going about their day, by now most things were open, as we laboured though the streets navigating the donkeys and goats that were hanging out like petulant teenagers.</p>

<p>When I said we worked together, what I meant was, I did what he did. This man who oozed cycling experience became my link to my purpose as I started to lose grip on reality a little. When he drank, I drank. When he got out of his saddle, I got out of my saddle.</p>

<p>With 3km to go, everything was hurting. What I thought had been the pain cave on the final 2km of the first ascent was actually a charming pied-a-tierre with sea views. Everything was hurting. I was having trouble focusing. I was empty. I was a pedalling automoton.</p>

<p>I finally lost his wheel on the last hairpin and found myself close to tears as walkers skipped gaily passed.</p>

<p>And then it was over. I was shaking. 2 cans of coke, a massive salad and a coffee as I sat bathed in sun outside the restaurant at the top soon restored me to some measure of health and sanity. Quick photo and then off down to make sure I made the lunchtime slot for the road reopening.</p>

<p>Another wonderful descent reminded me that I just love high mountain descents. There is something glorious about miles and miles of hurtling downhill.</p>

<p>The road from Luz to Argeles-Gazost, where we are staying, runs through a gorge and it's here I had my Jérémy Roy moment. As I hurtled along the gorge through the rock-fall tunnels, pedalling furiously dragging the last drops of energy from my aching legs I felt like I was in a Pyrenean TDF stage. I been out on a breakaway in the high mountains all day, see Jérémy Roy in 2012 Tour, and was gunning for the finish in of the valley towns.</p>

<p>Then my back said don't be so stupid, you're 41 and somewhat out of condition.</p>

<p>Oh and there absolutely wasn't a festival-come-market thing just below the Tourmalet on the west side that meant that roadworks and thus road closures had been suspended to ensure people could get to it.</p>

<p>So I needn't have got up at 5:30 but I'm kinda glad I did.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pre cycle commute UK weather forecast tweet]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambird.com/pre-cycle-commute-uk-weather-forecast-tweet"/>
    <updated>2013-05-12T20:57:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambird.com/pre-cycle-commute-uk-weather-forecast-tweet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing around (<a href="../pushing-info-to-pebble-watch">see here</a>) and have set up a simple service that tweets me every morning at 7:30am with a simple weather forecast. Importantly it has the information I want as a cycle commuter.</p>

<ul>
<li>Wind speed &amp; direction</li>
<li>Likelihood of rain</li>
<li>Temperature</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<p>The result looks a bit like this</p>

<pre><code>@adambird
Mon 13 - BEESTON
11C Light rain
11mph WSW
Rain 84%
</code></pre>

<p>It's just one less thing to have to look at in the morning.</p>

<p>Would you like to receive the messages too?</p>

<p>I've got some ideas for developing it and if there's enough interest I will. It doesn't cost me anything to run other than time at the moment so I thought it was worth putting out there.</p>

<p>If you'd like to give it a go. Then adam dot bird at gmail dot com or @adambird and let me know</p>

<ol>
<li>Where you want the forecast for</li>
<li>What time you want it</li>
</ol>


<p>Also any thoughts on what info would be useful to you before you assemble your commuting accessories and attire would be much appreciated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mamil and proud]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambird.com/mamil-and-proud"/>
    <updated>2010-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambird.com/mamil-and-proud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read with some amusement the recent BBC article about Middle Aged Men In Lycra, Mamils (<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-10965608)">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-10965608)</a>. Yes much of it rang true but I can't help feeling that there is an element of cynicism and sneering that drives that sort of moniker. <p /> It's the same in most sports-cum-leisure activities. The hard-core of 'real' participants look down their noses at these johnny-cum-latelys as some how not worthy of participating in 'their' sport. Turn-up on something expensive with which to participate in the sport like a carbon race frame or high-end clothing and this just fuels their derision. <p /> As an owner of much high-quality kit and no points to my racing name I am truly a Mamil to be derided. It's all about the legs apparently. If you haven't got the legs you should know your place and let the real-men show you how it's done. <p /> And they've done it the hard way. <p /> Balls to the hard-way. I was never very sporty and spent my twenties abusing my body with booze and fags. So no school of hard knocks apprenticeship for me but I have reached middle-age with kids and a decent career. So now I'm short on time and have a bit of disposable income. <p /> Being able to afford decent kit is brilliant. <p /> Beating other people is great too but bike races only have one winner out of anything up to 100 entrants so chances are high it's not going to be me. With that in mind I intend to enjoy myself riding in the bunch, putting myself in the mix and seeing which way the dice fall. <p /> Doing that in the best kit I'm prepared to afford just adds to the fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knackered Mamil Syndrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambird.com/knackered-mamil-syndrome"/>
    <updated>2010-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambird.com/knackered-mamil-syndrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Competitive cycling is a demanding mistress. Couple that with a career and a family and you have a recipe for doing some serious damage to yourself. <p /> I sit here after two months of enforced cycling lay-off through being repeatedly ill and am forced to reflect on what went wrong. Blood tests show me to be in super shape but I still can't do any exercise without developing some kind of illness. Sore throat, aching, headaches, etc, etc. The conclusion that my doctor has come to is that I've trained and worked myself into the ground. I'm just knackered. Unable to fight off the day to day infections we never normally notice. <p /> I have a hard and demanding job and a wonderful, but demanding family (in a good way, obviously). Training happens in the early hours before the the rest of the family stir. Sleep and rest are something that fits in around everything else and generally I try and get away with the minimum. <p /> My job also involves some long-haul travel and I have seen it as a fantastic opportunity to get some training in. Last time I was in San Francisco, I embraced the jet-lag so it was easy to get up for training at 5am, get 3 hours of hard miles in before spending the day working. Invariably catching up on emails from the UK before going to bed later than I should. Being away from the family though meant my time was my own and thus it was an opportunity to train, not to be missed. <p /> Crashing in the Alps probably didn't help either but however much I try and rationalise it all and be pragmatic I can't help feeling I'm sitting here watching another season drift by with nothing to show for it. And that hurts, a lot. <p /> I'm currently the right side of 40 but not by much and with coming to cycling late I'm desperate to maximise my achievements. Being driven helps me train hard but this has shown me that I need to actually act on all that advice that says rest is a key component of training. Being driven and dumb and is no use to anyone. <p /> So next year is a new approach. Train hard, absolutely, but only when I feel up for it. Move rest and recovery to number 3 in the priority list, after family and work, and see what results materialise.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
