<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cycling | Bird Stream]]></title>
  <link href="http://adambird.com/blog/categories/cycling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://adambird.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-30T20:51:55+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://adambird.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knackered Mamil Syndrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://adambird.com/knackered-mamil-syndrome"/>
    <updated>2010-08-27T11:02:55+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://adambird.com/knackered-mamil-syndrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Competitive cycling is a demanding mistress. Couple that with a career and a family and you have a recipe for doing some serious damage to yourself. <p /> I sit here after two months of enforced cycling lay-off through being repeatedly ill and am forced to reflect on what went wrong. Blood tests show me to be in super shape but I still can't do any exercise without developing some kind of illness. Sore throat, aching, headaches, etc, etc. The conclusion that my doctor has come to is that I've trained and worked myself into the ground. I'm just knackered. Unable to fight off the day to day infections we never normally notice. <p /> I have a hard and demanding job and a wonderful, but demanding family (in a good way, obviously). Training happens in the early hours before the the rest of the family stir. Sleep and rest are something that fits in around everything else and generally I try and get away with the minimum. <p /> My job also involves some long-haul travel and I have seen it as a fantastic opportunity to get some training in. Last time I was in San Francisco, I embraced the jet-lag so it was easy to get up for training at 5am, get 3 hours of hard miles in before spending the day working. Invariably catching up on emails from the UK before going to bed later than I should. Being away from the family though meant my time was my own and thus it was an opportunity to train, not to be missed. <p /> Crashing in the Alps probably didn't help either but however much I try and rationalise it all and be pragmatic I can't help feeling I'm sitting here watching another season drift by with nothing to show for it. And that hurts, a lot. <p /> I'm currently the right side of 40 but not by much and with coming to cycling late I'm desperate to maximise my achievements. Being driven helps me train hard but this has shown me that I need to actually act on all that advice that says rest is a key component of training. Being driven and dumb and is no use to anyone. <p /> So next year is a new approach. Train hard, absolutely, but only when I feel up for it. Move rest and recovery to number 3 in the priority list, after family and work, and see what results materialise.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mamil and proud]]></title>
    <link href="http://adambird.com/mamil-and-proud"/>
    <updated>2010-08-27T11:01:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://adambird.com/mamil-and-proud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read with some amusement the recent BBC article about Middle Aged Men In Lycra, Mamils (<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-10965608)">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-10965608)</a>. Yes much of it rang true but I can't help feeling that there is an element of cynicism and sneering that drives that sort of moniker. <p /> It's the same in most sports-cum-leisure activities. The hard-core of 'real' participants look down their noses at these johnny-cum-latelys as some how not worthy of participating in 'their' sport. Turn-up on something expensive with which to participate in the sport like a carbon race frame or high-end clothing and this just fuels their derision. <p /> As an owner of much high-quality kit and no points to my racing name I am truly a Mamil to be derided. It's all about the legs apparently. If you haven't got the legs you should know your place and let the real-men show you how it's done. <p /> And they've done it the hard way. <p /> Balls to the hard-way. I was never very sporty and spent my twenties abusing my body with booze and fags. So no school of hard knocks apprenticeship for me but I have reached middle-age with kids and a decent career. So now I'm short on time and have a bit of disposable income. <p /> Being able to afford decent kit is brilliant. <p /> Beating other people is great too but bike races only have one winner out of anything up to 100 entrants so chances are high it's not going to be me. With that in mind I intend to enjoy myself riding in the bunch, putting myself in the mix and seeing which way the dice fall. <p /> Doing that in the best kit I'm prepared to afford just adds to the fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty]]></title>
    <link href="http://adambird.com/beauty"/>
    <updated>2010-08-10T22:23:35+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://adambird.com/beauty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All assembled, quick spin round the block for a few adjustments and I'm ready for tomorrow's inaugural run. <p /> First impressions are that it is wonderfully responsive frame that is demanding to be ridden quickly. <p /> Happy to oblige.<img src="http://adambird.com/images/beauty/photo.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internal cable routing on the Cervélo, easy]]></title>
    <link href="http://adambird.com/internal-cable-routing-on-the-cervelo-easy"/>
    <updated>2010-08-09T23:42:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://adambird.com/internal-cable-routing-on-the-cervelo-easy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wasn't looking forward to this aspect of the build. Was envisaging a frustrating evening of poking and fiddling but it was actually very easy. <p /> The gear cables just appeared at the bottom and the only slightly tricky item was the rear brake cable in the top tube. A pair it needle-nose pliers had that sorted in no time. <p /> Crankset and chain are going on tomorrow. Even without those it's starting to feel like a bike. <p /> Boy it feels good.<img src="http://adambird.com/images/internal-cable-routing-on-the-cervelo-easy/photo.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
